

Seasoned network engineer with over IQ years of experience and 4+years in a senior role. Outstanding knowledge of network security protocols and talented at analyzing and assessing networks to ensure data security. Strong team player with a proven track record for training junior staff and performance management.

Professional Experience

Senior Network Engineer

Kforce Technology Staffing, Austin, TX September 2016- Present

- Lead and work collaboratively with team members to design and implement upgrades and improvements, increasing performance by 65% in 2020
- Train up to 25 interns and new hires per year to boost their technical and industry knowledge
- Aetas an escalation point for the most complex network errors, troubleshooting
 95% of problems within 3 hours in 2020
- Closely monitor network performance and generate solutions to recurring issues

Network Engineer

Insight Networking, Austin, TX July 2010 - September 2016

- Diagnosed and resolved LAN and WAN connection problems for multiple clients
- Maintained up-to-date and error-free recordsand documentation for clients' networks, achieving 99.9% accuracy during spot checks
- Made recommendations for system upgrades to improve connection security, reliability, and speed
- Provided informal mentorship and support to colleagues to help them solve straightforward IT and networking issues

123 Ad dress Road, Austin, TX 65432 I m .sawyer® myemai I .com (890) 123-4567

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Texas State University, Round Rock, TX September 2004 - June 2008

Master of Computer Science University Of Texas, Austin, TX September 2008 - June 2010

Key Skills

- Customer service
- Leadership and training
- Firewalls and security
- DNS
- MPLS
- Troubleshooting and maintenance